Jon Connor, Dublin, Ireland. 087 1374592

jonconnor@live.ie

Motivated Software Tester with 5 years of progressive experience in the Software Testing industry. Offering expertise in manual and automated testing, planning and reviewing with aptitude in requirements gathering. Energetic self-starter and team builder able to navigate high-stress situations and achieve goals on time.

Current Certification

- ISTQB BCS Certified Agile Tester Extension (FLA)
- ISTQB BCS Certified Tester Foundation Level (ISEB-SWT2)
- City & Guilds Level 2 Software Testing (7540-12-012)
- Microsoft Technical Associate Database Fundamentals (98-364)
- Selenium WebDriver for Beginners using JAVA (UDEMY course)
- Selenium WebDriver with Java-Basics to Advanced Frameworks, cucumber and gherkin (UDEMY course)

Key Skills

- Review, understand and interpret Business Requirements
- Behaviour Driven Development (Cucumber and Gherkin)
- Communicating effectively with stakeholders and vendors to keep projects on track
- Advocating for the end user throughout the development
- Testing Software to ensure compliance with Business Requirements
- Accurately record and track identified defects using JIRA
- Work with developers to achieve resolution of defects
- Conduct functional tests using black box techniques
- Analysis of actual results arising from test execution
- Advanced Excel functions
- Foundation level knowledge of SQL
- Version control using Git
- Java and Selenium Test Automation

Experience

Contract QA Engineer, SAP Ariba, Dublin (Employed via Manpower Ireland)

August 2020 – Present

Working in the QA department of the localisation team. Reviewing strings for translatability, updating and fixing automated scripts to capture screen shots of "new" strings to aid translation. Then ensuring the translation has not affected the functionality of the translated screens by running the scripts in the localised languages. Using JIRA to investigate new features for new strings and either update existing scripts or create new ones. Have increased the overnight pass rates from 30% to 60% by using pre-created events in the scripts rather than creating the event from scratch in the scripts.

Contract Software Tester, Accounting Technicians Ireland, Dublin 2

April 2018 – March 2020

Successfully implemented an assessment module in the new CRM software package by identifying missing requirements in the developer's specifications from the test cases I wrote for coverage of the business rules. Working on a membership module to add to the CRM and enhancing an existing apprentice module to accommodate new business vision and requirements. Using cucumber and gherkin to develop and produce business requirements for these new modules.

Software Tester, Interactive Services, Dublin 15

May 2017 – April 2018

Responsible for the testing within a development team that specializes in the localization of e-learning courses for the financial services sectors. There was no formal test plan, so I developed and implemented a test charter, so all software released was at an acceptable standard. Client fixes for functionality dropped dramatically. Upskilled in HTML/CSS and GIT so that I could fix minor text and graphics issues. The Project Manager would receive minor issues from client and assign to me to fix. I would then assign back to Project Manager to keep independence in the fix and verify bug cycle. This freed up programmers to do more urgent and important tasks in the project.

Warehouse Tester, Actavo (In Home Division), Dublin 12

August 2016 – April 2017

Tested set top boxes (SKY TV) to confirm faulty using a series of manual tests. Updated the stock on the company's system and organised return to the client. By asking the business leaders and managers questions about the high level of set top boxes that were incorrectly assigned as faulty. I could see the negative impact it had on the business. I created a simple spreadsheet that recorded every set top box I tested along with Engineer ID, Team, Team Manager and Area Manager. I was then able to identify which Engineers, Teams, Managers and Area Managers were having issues diagnosing faulty set top boxes. Extra training was arranged, and the non-faulty boxes returned as faulty steadily dropped to an acceptable level.

Temporary Software Tester, Interactive Services, Dublin 15

October 2015 – August 2016

Obtained a 4-week work placement via ETB training course. Was kept on in a temporary basis testing various types of custom E-Learning solutions for Fortune 500 companies such as Coca Cola, Deloitte, Facebook, Hershey, LinkedIn, Morgan Stanley, United Airlines, VISA and Walmart. Regression testing, checking functionality, localization testing, and working on a new template to ensure functionality and display was consistent over numerous browsers, devices and OS using emulators and the actual devices.

Project Manager, Resource and Environmental Consultants, Dublin 10

January 2012 – March 2015

Responsible for the resourcing, scheduling and reporting of stack emission monitoring projects carried out by the business in Ireland. Worked to INAB (ISO 17025) and UKAS MCERTS accredited procedures. Prepared client and site-specific protocols for monitoring their emissions to the atmosphere. Collated the data collected on site by my team and other teams to produce technical reports for clients for their environmental regulatory bodies, EPA and local councils.

Pre-2011

Emissions testing roles and 12 years in a quality assurance and quality control role for a manufacturer of adhesive papers and vinyl.

Education

St Bede's RC College, Manchester

1983 - 1990

- 4 GCE A- Level: Pure Mathematics with Mechanics, Physics, Chemistry & General Studies
- 8 GCSE including English & Mathematics